# ANDIKA PUTRA GUMILANG

Merak Street, Jakasetia, South Bekasi, West Java, 17147. (+62)8211 0065 957. andikapg19@gmail.com

## **ABOUT**

A Young professional, eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail, and excellent organization skills. Having more than 5 years of dedication in Sales Management, Planning, Analyst, and Operation.

A Data Analyst & Data Science Enthusiast. Highly passionate about numbers and statistics, have some experience partaking in several analytical competitions at Kaggle, and recently won 1<sup>st</sup> place for best final project in Full-Stack Data Analytics Bootcamp.

I have a strong belief that when you want something, all the universe conspires in helping you to achieve it.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

#### PT. GOTO (GOJEK TOKOPEDIA)

#### **■** Account Manager Supervisor GOFOOD (November 2020 – Present)

Developing strategies to maximize business potential, Providing imperative discussion with GOFOOD merchant Owners to increase their income by using GOJEK products, Maintaining 10 Billion GOFOOD sales/ month, and Sustaining relationships with 1.000 outlets,

## • PT. AMERTA INDAH OTSUKA (POCARI SWEAT)

#### **■** Head Of Area (June 2017 – October 2020)

Responsible for operational and sales activity, including distribution products to all channels (General Trade and Modern Trade), Maintaining sales growth, Doing marketing activity, Sustaining strong relationships with the top 50 outlets, and Ensuring relations for business interest between PT. Amerta Indah Otsuka and Distributor are well intertwined.

- Head of Area Makassar (October 2018 – October 2021)

Handling 1 main distributor with 8 sub-distributor with average sales 3,5 billion/month, managing 2 Supervisor for general trade with 12 sales team, and 1 Supervisor modern trade with 2 sales,2 merchandisers, and having 4.000 outlets around South and West Sulawesi Province

- Head Of Area Lhokseumawe (January 2018 – September 2018)

Handling 1 main distributor with 2 sub-distributor with average sales 700 million/month, managing 2 Supervisor with 5 sales team, and having 1.000 outlets around Aceh Province

- Head Of Area South East Sulawesi (September 2017 – December 2017)

Handling 1 main distributor with 2 sub-distributor with average sales 700 million/month, managing 2 supervisor with 6 sales team, and having 1.300 outlets around East Sulawesi Province

## **■** Management Trainee (October 2016 – August 2017)

A program that is Built to prepare employees to get capable skills to occupy a managerial position

- Head Of Area Makassar (June 2017 – August 2017)

Handling 1 main distributor with average sales 2 billion/month, managing 1 Supervisor for general trade with 7 sales team, and 1 supervisor modern trade with 2 Sales, 2 merchandisers, and having around 2.000 outlets around South Sulawesi Province

- Internal Auditor (April 2017 – May 2017)

Analyzing & Observing system internal to ensure the system run well and effectively

Project: Initiating to create a distribution map to maintain distribution density

- Sales Supervisor (January 2017 – March 2017)

Maintaining sales performance in area and Managing 3 sales team and 3 assistant sales having around 1.500 outlets

- Sales & Assistant Sales (October 2016- December 2016)

Maintaining sales performance in area, Distributing products to 500 outlets, Cleaning office vehicles every early morning before the daily briefing, and loading products from warehouse.

# ORGANIZATION & PROJECT

## Head of Sales Department Youth Speak Summit – AIESEC 2016

This is the main event of YouthSpeak forum that held in 11 big cities all over Indonesia, The summit is a one day conference with a Grand Theme of Mobilizing Indonesia Youth toward Sustainable Development Goals which is initiated by the United Nations and powered by AIESEC I was responsible for financial support in term of Sponsorship and Partnership. Including market research based on CSR, Approaching company through LinkedIn and official website and Conducting a formal and informal meeting

# Comitte Festival Olahraga dan Seni (FORSI) UNPAD

FORSI is the biggest event at Padjadjaran University, 16 faculty and more than 10.000 people get involved in this event,

#### Head of Marketing Department FORSI 2015

I was responsible for financial support. I had 20 staff in my department, and I divided into 3 divisions: Sponsorship Division, Media Partner Division, And Entrepreneur(tenant) division. We got more than 200millions from companies, we got more than 30 Media Partners, And more than 50 Entrepreneurs(tenants) involved in our project.

#### Coordinator Opening Event FORSI 2014

I was responsible for the Opening Event, I had more than 20 technical staff, and I made the event flow, such as the concept of the parade that was followed by 16 faculties with more then 2.000 people involved in this opening parade, stage performances and festive opening ceremony.

#### **EDUCATION**

# UNIVERSITY OF PADJADJARAN (2011-2016)

Bachelor of Engineering (GPA 3.32)

**DQLAB (2020 - 2021)** 

Data Analyst Class. Learning Skills for being a data analyst, starting with SQL, and Python Programming Language

**REVOU (2022)** 

Full Stack Data Analyst – Learning Skills and also building a portfolio for being a data analyst by working with real clients

# **ACHIEVEMENT**

- 1ST Best Final Group Project Full Stack Data Analyst REVOU (2022) (I Became Project Leader with 2 Members)
- 3rd Best Graduate of Sales Development Program PT. Amerta Indah Otsuka Batch 10
- 2 Education Scholarship From INDOSAT (2010-2015)

#### **ADDITIONAL**

Software Proficiency

Microsoft Office : Advance SQL : Intermediate (Certified Fundamental SQL By Dqlab)

Google Data Studio: Intermediate Python: Intermediate (Certified Phyton for Data Professional By Dqlab)

Big Query Google: Intermediete Tableau: Intermediete

Language Proficiency

TOEFL (515), Bahasa Indonesia

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/andika-gumilang-6aa09b113